fontfeed.com 2017-06-23

# FontShop

## Terms and Conditions of Use

### 1\. Content of online-offers

Monotype GmbH is anxious to offer the information completely and in continuously high quality as well as always up-to-date. Nevertheless, Monotype GmbH does not take over any guarantee for the topicality, correctness, completeness and the quality of the information supplied on this page. 

Monotype GmbH excludes any liability for slightly negligent breaches of duty provided that it does not concern essential contractual obligations, life, health or body or claims concerning the german product liability law. All supplies offered on this page are not-binding and noncommittal. All specification is given by Monotype GmbH after best knowledge; mistakes are excluded. 

Monotype GmbH reserves the right to expressly change individual sections of the on-line supply or the entire supply without further notice to complete or to stop the entire on-line supply for a certain time or forever.

### 2\. Copyrights

All data—especially the databases—of this website enjoy proprietary protection according to § 4 and § 87 a et seq. copyright law. Editing or copying is only permitted if necessary for access to the databases or their general use. All additional edits, copies or distributions and/or public re-production, especially unapproved adoption to an internet- or intranet-offer is an exceeding of the standard appraisal of the databases and therefore will be considered as an infringement of copyrights which will be prosecuted and obliges to payment of indemnifications. 

Monotype GmbH is anxious to consider in its publications all copyrights of used graphics, audio-documents, video sequences and texts, to use its own graphics, audio-documents, video sequences and texts or to access licensed graphics, audio-documents, video sequences and texts. All patent design rights and trademarks mentioned in the online-offer or protected by third parties are all exclusively subject to the provisions of the respective valid identification law and the respective registered proprietor. Based on a statement not including a trademark reference, it shall not be concluded that trademarks are not protected by rights of third parties! 

Copyrights for objects published and used by Monotype GmbH remain with Monotype GmbH. Copies or usage of such graphics, audio-documents, video sequences and texts in other electronic or printed publications is not permitted without expressly consent of Monotype GmbH.

### 3\. Data security

If there is the possibility for input of personal or business data within the internet supply, the input of such data takes place basically voluntarily by the user. 

Personal data used by us in the framework of contract preparation/order processing are saved and only passed on to third parties for this purpose exclusively. In all other respects we use the respective data with justified interest of our company for purposes of credit verifications only if necessary.

### 4\. Legal effect

The foresaid rules for non-warranty clause are an essential element of these online offers. They are valid for all pages of the offer. As far as several wordings of references to adhesion or only parts of it should be effect-less or should become effect-less, the effectiveness of all other clauses will remain unaffected thereof.

### 5\. Forward-Looking Statements

This website contains express or implied forward-looking statements within the meaning of the United States Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995, which are based on the current expectations of the management of Monotype GmbH. These statements relate to, among other things, our expectations regarding our products and management’s plans, objectives and strategies. These statements are neither promises nor guarantees, but are subject to a variety of risks and uncertainties, many of which are beyond our control, and which could cause actual results to differ materially from those contemplated in these forward-looking statements. 

In particular, the risks and uncertainties include, among other things, the timing of scheduled updates to our products and the expected performance of our products. Monotype GmbH assumes no obligation to update any forward-looking statements contained on this website in the event of changing circumstances or otherwise and such statements are current only as of the date they are first posted to the website by Monotype GmbH.

### 6\. Updates

Monotype GmbH may make improvements and/or changes to this website at any time. Although we attempt to periodically update information on this website, the information, materials and services provided on or through this website may occasionally be inaccurate, incomplete or out of date. Monotype GmbH does not have a duty to update information contained in this website, and Monotype GmbH will not be liable for any failure to update such information. We make no representation as to the completeness, accuracy or currentness of any information on this website, and we undertake no obligation to update or revise the information contained on this website, whether as a result of new information, future events or circumstances or otherwise. It is your responsibility to verify any information contained in this website before relying upon it.

### 7\. Links

This website may contain links to websites operated by other parties. Such linked sites are not under the control of Monotype GmbH and Monotype GmbH is not responsible for the content available on any other Internet sites linked to this website. Such links do not imply Monotype GmbH’s endorsement of material on any other site, and Monotype GmbH disclaims all liability with regard to your access to such linked websites. Monotype GmbH provides links to other Internet sites as a convenience to uses, and access to any other Internet sites linked to this website is at your own risk.

### 8\. This Website Does not Provide Legal or Professional Services Advice

The content on this website is intended to be a general information resource in regard to the subject matter covered. Monotype GmbH is not a law firm and it does not directly or indirectly practice law, render legal advice or dispense legal services via this website. 

Nothing contained in this website is intended to be instruction for legal representation or to establish an attorney-client relationship. Any information provided on this website is not guaranteed to be correct, complete or up-do-date. The law changes frequently, is different from jurisdiction to jurisdiction and is also subject to different interpretations from different courts. **This website is not a substitute for the advice an attorney.**

### Last updated 1st December 2014

* * *

## Terms and Conditions of Business

We recommend that you print these Terms and Conditions of Business for further reference.

### 1\. Scope

The following Terms and Conditions will apply exclusively to the current and future business relationships between Monotype Imaging Inc. (collectively with its subsidiaries and affiliated companies, “Monotype”) and you (“you” or the “customer”). Any additional or inconsistent terms issued by you, including any such terms and conditions set forth on a purchase order provided by you shall not be binding upon Monotype, unless Monotype gives its express agreement in writing.

### 2\. Entire Agreement

Any quotation or price information made available by Monotype is without obligation and subject to change without notice unless an offer has been designated as binding. Oral understandings between you and Monotype will require written confirmation by Monotype and a contract between you and Monotype will only become valid when it has been accepted in writing by Monotype (e.g., confirmation of order, which will be final) or when the order is performed (e.g., delivery, download or connection by you of or to the software). As permitted by law, Monotype reserves the right to correct errors in its offers, invoices and communications such as spelling or arithmetical errors. You and Monotype each owe a duty to each other co-operate in order to give full effect to your agreement

### 3\. Assignment

Unless specifically set forth in a written agreement between you and Monotype, your obligations to Monotype may not be sublicensed or assigned to any third party (with a change in control of you constituting an assignment). These Terms and Conditions shall be binding on each party’s successors and assigns.

### 4\. Delivery

As permitted by law, Monotype’s standard delivery terms are FOB origin.

### 5\. Prices

Unless otherwise indicated in writing by Monotype, all prices are quoted in US dollars and are exclusive of all taxes and duties imposed by any governmental authority and freight and shipping charges, all of which shall be paid by you.

### 6\. Payment

Unless specifically set forth in a written agreement between you and Monotype, payment for goods or services from Monotype is net thirty (30) days from the date of invoice. Overdue payments shall bear interest from the due date at the rate of the lower of one and half percent per month (1.5%) or the maximum rate permissible under applicable law.

### 7\. Warranty

Unless specifically set forth in a written agreement between you and Monotype or as required by law, the goods and services purchased by you are provided _“as is”_ without any representation or warranty of any kind, including without limitation, any warranty of non-infringement or fitness for a particular purpose.

### 8\. Partial Nullity

In the event that any provision of these Terms and Conditions is unenforceable or invalid, such unenforceability or invalidity shall not render these Terms and Conditions unenforceable or invalid as a whole, and, in such event, such provision shall be changed and interpreted so as to best accomplish the objectives of such unenforceable or invalid provision within the limits of applicable law or court decisions.

### 9\. Export

You agree that the software licensed to you by Monotype will not be shipped, transferred or exported into any country or used in any manner prohibited by the United States Export Administration or any applicable export laws, restrictions or regulations.

### 10\. U.S. Government Contracts

If the software licensed to you by Monotype is acquired under the terms of a (i) GSA contract – use, reproduction or disclosure is subject to the restrictions set forth in the applicable ADP Schedule contract, (ii) DOD contract – use, duplication or disclosure by the Government is subject to the applicable restrictions set forth in DFARS 252.277-7013; (iii) Civilian agency contract – use, reproduction, or disclosure is subject to FAR 52.277-19(a) through (d) and restrictions set forth in your agreement with Monotype.

### 11\. Governing Law and Jurisdiction

Unless you enter into this agreement through the Monotype affiliate Monotype Ltd. or Monotype GmbH, or unless otherwise set forth in writing in the agreement between you and Monotype, the agreement entered into between you and Monotype is governed by the laws of Massachusetts applicable to contracts wholly entered and performable within such Commonwealth (without regard to applicable conflict of laws provisions). The United States District Court for the District of Massachusetts or, if federal subject matter jurisdiction is lacking, the Superior Court of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts in Middlesex County, shall be the exclusive forum for any disputes arising out of or related to such agreement. Both you and Monotype agree to the personal jurisdiction and venue of these courts in any action related to such agreement.

If you enter into this agreement through the Monotype affiliate Monotype Ltd. the agreement is governed by the laws of England and Wales (without regard to applicable conflict of laws provi-sions). The courts of London, England, shall be the exclusive forum for any disputes arising out of or related to such agreement. Both you and Monotype Ltd. agree to the personal jurisdiction and venue of these courts in any action related to such agreement.

If you enter into this agreement through the Monotype affiliate Monotype GmbH the agreement is governed by the laws of Germany (without regard to applicable conflict of laws provisions). The courts of Frankfurt/Main, Germany, shall be the ex-clusive forum for any disputes arising out of or related to such agreement. Both you and Monotype GmbH agree to the personal jurisdiction and venue of these courts in any action related to such agreement.

The agreement will not be governed by the United Nations Convention of Contracts for the International Sale of Goods, the application of which is expressly excluded.

### Last updated 1st December 2014

* * *

## Privacy Policy

Monotype GmbH, Werner-Reimers-Straße 2–4, 61352 Bad Homburg, Germany (collectively, “Monotype”) makes information, products, and services available on our Web sites (each individually, the “Site” and collectively, the “Sites”), subject to the following Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”). We own and operate many Sites, for instance FontShop.com. You can determine if Monotype is the owner and operator of a site by referring to the Terms and Conditions of Use for the specific site. The Privacy Policy applies to all of our Sites. 

### Monotype’s Commitment to Personal Information Protection

At Monotype, we respect your right to privacy. Protecting the security and privacy of your personal information is important to us. We understand that as a visitor to our Site, you prefer to control your own personal information preferences and we give you the option to do so. We hope the policy outlined below will help you understand what personal information we may collect, how we use and safeguard that personal information and with whom we may share it.

### Voluntary Personal Information We May Collect

We may ask you to register or provide personal information and preferences when you visit certain areas of our Site, request information, purchase products or subscribe to company newsletters. When you provide Monotype with your name, email address, mailing address, or telephone number, and you don’t “opt-out”, we may use this information to alert you to company news, new services and other company and product information. If you don’t want Monotype or Monotype representatives to contact you, you may “opt-out” of this preference at any time, whether you’re online or contacting Monotype directly. You’ll always have the flexibility to “opt-in” at any time based on previous information or newly updated information. 

### Non-Voluntary Personal Information We May Collect

When you browse our Site, you can generally do so anonymously as we don’t collect personal information when you browse; however, your browser automatically tells us the type of computer and operating system you’re using. Like most standard Web site servers, our Site uses log files (cookies). A “cookie” is a small line of text that is stored with your Web browser for record-keeping purposes and helps Monotype provide better service to you. Your browser has an option to accept, reject or provide you with notice when a cookie is sent. Once you enter our Site, a cookie follows as you navigate the site, collecting information including internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer the site, track users’ overall movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use only, to help us understand what users are seeking on our Site.

### Purpose of Collecting Personal Information

When you do provide us with personal data, we usually use it to respond to your inquiry, process your order or provide you access to specific information or offers. Also, to support our customer relationship with you, we may store and process voluntary and non-voluntary personal data and share it with our worldwide affiliates to better understand your business needs and how we can improve our products and services. If you choose not to have your personal data used to support our customer relationship (especially direct marketing or market research), we will respect your choice. We do not sell or otherwise market your personal data to third parties.

### Limitation on the Purpose

We collect, use or disclose personal information supplied by you only for the purpose(s) initially identified by you, however, in some cases we may use the personal information supplied by you: (i) for any additional purpose that is directly related to the original purpose for which the personal information was collected, including sharing such personal information with a third party vendor if you purchased a product supplied by that third party vendor from one of our Sites, (ii) when it is necessary to prepare, negotiate and perform a contract with you, (iii) when it is required by law or the competent governmental or judicial authorities, (iv) when it is necessary to establish or preserve a legal claim or defense, or (v) when it is necessary to prevent fraud or other illegal activities.

### How We Protect Your Personal Information

Monotype uses its best efforts to try to protect the personal information that you share with us. Monotype stores information in a controlled, secure environment. We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, however we only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

### How to Update Your Personal Information or “Opt-out”

You can help Monotype maintain the accuracy of your personal information by notifying us when you change your name, address, title, phone number, e-mail address or your content preferences. If at any time you wish to update your information or preferences, or you prefer to stop receiving communication from Monotype, feel free to contact us at any time.

### Links to Other Sites

Our Site may contain links to other Sites. Monotype assumes no responsibility for the content or the privacy policies and practices of such Web sites. Monotype encourages you to read the privacy statements of the linked sites as their privacy practices may differ from ours.

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (‘Google’). Google Analytics uses ‘cookies,’ which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. In the event IP anonymization is activated on this website, your IP address will be shortened beforehand by Google within member states of the European Union or in other signatory states of the Treaty on the European Economic Area. The full IP address will be transmitted to a Google Server in the USA and shortened there only on an exceptional basis. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators, and providing other services to website operators relating to website activity and Internet usage. Google will not associate the IP address transmitted under Google Analytics by your browser with other data held by Google. You may prevent the storage of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser software; however, we must advise you that in this case, you might not be able to use all functions of this website to the full extent. You may prevent Google from recording the data generated by the cookie and pertaining to your use of the website (including your IP address), or processing these data by downloading and installing the following browser plug-in available through the following link: [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

### Google AdWords Conversion Tracking

This website uses Google AdWords Conversion Tracking, a web analysis service of Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google AdWords Conversion Tracking also uses “cookies,” which are stored on your computer and facilitate an analysis of how you use the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website will be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity for website operators, and to provide other services related to website use and Internet use. Google will also transmit this information to third parties, where applicable, if this is required by law or to the extent third parties process this data on behalf of Google. Google will not link this data with other Google data under any circumstances. You can prevent the use of cookies in general if you disallow the storage of cookies on your browser.

### AddThis Plugins

This website features the bookmarking service AddThis’ plugins so that you can bookmark interesting content. Use of the AddThis service creates cookies. The data generated in this process (e.g. time of use or browser language) are transferred to Add This LLC in the USA and stored there. Please visit [](http://www.addthis.com/privacy)[www.addthis.com/privacy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy) for further information about data processing by Add This LLC and its privacy policy. It specifies the type of data processed and the purpose of processing. We do not process these data. If you use the AddThis button, you declare your consent to the processing of your data by Add This LLC to the extent specified on [www.addthis.com](http://www.addthis.com/). You can prevent the use of your data at any time with an opt-out cookie.

### Disqus Plugin

This website uses the discussion tool [Disqus](http://www.disqus.com/). This allows users to post comments on our website/blog. A comment can be posted as a guest (without registration) or by using a Facebook, Twitter, Google or Disqus user account. When using Disqus with a social login from Facebook, Twitter or Google these services can also collect and store data (please also see the respective Privacy Policies for Facebook, Twitter or Google+). 

Disqus is an online service that offers a centralized discussion platform for websites. The technology used by Disqus is provided by the Big Head Labs, Inc. of San Francisco, USA. All data sent over the Disqus comment system will be processed and stored on their servers. The data is stored on servers outside Europe. For the storage, processing and collection of data by Disqus, its terms and conditions apply. You can find the Disqus Privacy Policy [here](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy). 

### Business Transitions Including Merger or Acquisition

If Monotype undergoes a business transition such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users’ personal information may become part of the assets transferred.

### Monotype Privacy Concerns Contacts

If you want to change your personal information or wish to “opt-out” log in to your personal account, and enter the following url: [www.fontshop.com/settings](http://www.fontshop.com/settings) to amend your details or contact us in the following ways:

#### E-mail:  

#### Common Carrier:

Monotype GmbH  
Werner-Reimers-Str. 2–4  
61352 Bad Homburg  
Germany  

 _Berlin office_  
Bergmannstr. 102  
10961 Berlin  
Germany  

### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement on our Site under the Privacy Policy section. You can determine when these Terms were last revised by referring to the _“Last updated”_ line at the bottom of these Terms. Your continued use of the Site after any changes to the site will indicate your acceptance of the changes and Terms.

### Last updated 29nd March 2016

## Trademarks

Please see Trademarks
